Warren Roberts Papers, 1959-1985.
University of Houston Libraries
Warren Roberts Papers
1959-1985
Roberts, Warren
2 boxes, 262 items
1987-004
Special Collections, University of Houston Libraries
(Francis) Warren Roberts has had an active publishing career, focusing a great deal of his time and effort on editing the works of D. H. Lawrence. He has also published additional works on D. H. Lawrence. The majority of the collection relate to activities of the Grolier Club, of which Roberts is a member, and publications for D. H. Lawrence works, symposia, and related activities. Among the D. H. Lawrence materials are issues of several newsletters, including D. H. Lawrence News and Notes, Lawrence Country News, and the Newsletter of the D.H. Lawrence Society of North America.
Biographical Note
(Francis) Warren Roberts was born in Menard, Texas in 1916. He received his Bachelor of Arts degree in 1938 from Southwestern University, and received his doctorate in 1956 from the University of Texas. He spent much of his academic career at the University of Texas at Austin, first as a professor of English, then as director of the Humanities Research Center from 1962 until 1978. The Humanities Research Center is now known as the Harry Ransom Humanities Research Center.
(Francis) Warren Roberts has had an active publishing career, focusing a great deal of his time and effort on editing the works of D. H. Lawrence. He has also published additional works on D. H. Lawrence. His interest and scholarly background in English literature are reflected in the materials he donated to the University of Houston Libraries' Special Collections.
Biographical information on (Francis) Warren Roberts is available from a number of sources, including the Directory of American Scholars, International Authors and Writers Who's Who, and Who's Who in America.
Scope and Contents
This collection includes materials collected or received by Warren Roberts during the 1960s, 1970s and 1980s. There are 262 items in the collection, dating between 1959 and 1985. The majority of the materials relate to activities of the Grolier Club, of which Roberts is a member, and publications for D. H. Lawrence works, symposia, and related activities.
Among the D. H. Lawrence materials are issues of several newsletters, including D. H. Lawrence News and Notes, Lawrence Country News, and the Newsletter of the D.H. Lawrence Society of North America. There are also notices for lectures and discussions regarding James Joyce and his works.
Additional materials include publications and brochures for conferences of rare book librarians and scholars, as well as sales information for books of interest to Roberts.
Materials have been arranged alphabetically by subject (Grolier Club, James Joyce, D. H. Lawrence, etc.). Single items unrelated to other materials have been grouped together within the Miscellaneous folder. Within each subject, items are arranged chronologically, with one exception. The book notices for D. H. Lawrence materials have been arranged alphabetically by title. Wherever possible, materials have been dated using a perpetual calendar.
The second box of material, Miscellaneous Oversize, includes three notices for new books on Texas history, a lecture announcement, and an issue of the University of Texas newspaper, The Texas Times, from August 1972 which is dedicated to Walter Prescott Webb.
A large number of print items donated to Special Collections and Archives by Warren Roberts are available for use in the reading room. These items have been cataloged and may be located using the library's online catalog. In addition, numerous broadsides and larger ephemeral items have been cataloged.
Index Terms
Terms are either Library of Congress Subject Headings or taken from local sources.
Subjects (Persons)
Roberts, Warren, 1916-; Lawrence, D. H. (David Herbert), 1885-1930; Webb, Walter Prescott, 1888-1963.
Subjects (Organizations)
University of Texas at Austin. Humanities Research Center; Grolier Club
Formats
Newsletters; Lectures; Publications; Brochures; Newspapers; Broadsides; Ephemera; Prints
Acquisition
This collection of materials is part of a much larger collection of printed works and ephemeral materials. The collection was donated to the University of Houston Libraries' Special Collections and Archives in 1987 by Warren Roberts. Additional materials donated by Dr. Warren Roberts have been cataloged and are held in Special Collections.
Open for research.
Detailed Description of the Collection
  - Greeting Cards, 1959-1974 (Box 1)
  - Grolier Club Lecture Invitations, 1970-1973 (Box 1)
  - Grolier Club Lecture Invitations, 1974-1976 (Box 1)
  - Grolier Club Lecture Invitations, 1977-1981 (Box 1)
  - Grolier Club Lecture Invitations, undated. (Box 1)
  - James Joyce Society Lectures, 1972-1975 (Box 1)
  - Lawrence, D.H.--Book Announcements, undated (Box 1)
  - Lawrence, D.H.--D.H. Lawrence News and Notes, 1959-1962 (Box 1)
  - Lawrence, D.H.--Invitations to Events, 1975-1980 (Box 1)
  - Lawrence, D.H.--Lawrence Country News, 1976-1978 (Box 1)
  - Lawrence, D.H.--Lawrence Country News, 1982-1984 (Box 1)
  - Lawrence, D.H.-Miscellaneous, 1964 (Box 1)
  - Lawrence, D.H.--Newsletter of the D.H. Lawrence Society of North America 1981-1984 (Box 1)
  - Lawrence, D.H.-Postcards, 1977-1982 (Box 1)
  - Lawrence, D.H.-Productions, 1961-1980 (Box 1)
  - Lawrence, D.H.--Seminars and Lectures, 1959-1985 (Box 1)
  - Miscellaneous, 1959-1981 (Box 1)
  - Texas Institute of Letters, 1976-1979 (Box 1)
  - University of Tulsa Library, 1978-1980 (Box 1)
  - Miscellaneous Oversize, 1969-1973 (Ovs 1)